



kuanyshboranbayev.herokuapp.comgithub.com/kboranbayev

n linkedin.com/in/kuanyshboranbayev

Software Developer

#### WHO AM I?

Dedicated and self-motivated Software Developer with 4 years experience and proficiency in the following: Nodejs, Reactjs, C, HTML and CSS, and AWS serverless architecture arsenal. Very familiar and experienced in modern MVC frameworks and SDLC. An excellent team worker. Advanced skills in network security and penetration testing. Advanced skills in network administration.

### **1Y SKILLS**

Software and Web Development:

GIT BASH PERL JENKINS JAVASCRIPT C/C++ HTML CSS PYTHON MONGODB REST API JAVA

Network Security and Administration

TCP/IP LAN/WAN VPN IDS FIREWALL ROUTING PROXY
REMOTE LOGGING SPLUNK WIRESHARK NMAP NETFILTER
FEDORA UBUNTU KALI AWS AZURE GOOGLE CLOUD PLATFORM
CRYPTOGRAPHY

**EXPERIENCE** 

2017 - 4/2017 part time

#### **Back-End Developer, Part-time**

**Denis Boyd & Associates** 

Designed and developed web application. Assisted in designing the backend architecture, handling the user registration, processing the payment, database processing, managing API calls, managing inbound and outbound rules for the instance.

node.js / expressjs / mongodb / jade / AWS EC2

2018 - 2019 Full Stack Developer, Full-time

Solo Project

Front-end developed using ReactJS and back-end is running using ExpressJS, and hosted on Heroku applications. Back-end is connected to Mongo DB which hosted on remote mLab server.

reactjs / semantic-ui / nodejs / mongodb / heroku / api

10/2019 - 2020 Full Stack Developer, Full-time

The Sheph.com Project

Designed back-end of the web application and implemented DB server on remote proxy server.

Implemented easily understandable REST API calls for front-end access.

reactjs / bootstrap / nodejs / AWS EC2 / heroku / mongodb / api

5/2019 – present **Customer Services, Part-time** 

Save-on-Foods

Resolve 20+ weekly customer inquiries. Assisted in training and mentoring new employees.

## **EDUCATION**

9/2019 - 4/2021 **Bachelor of Technology** 

British Columbia Institute of Technology

Network Security Applications Development, GPA: 86%

1/2016 - 12/2017 **Diploma** 

**British Columbia Institute of Technology** 

Computer Systems Technology with Cloud Computing Option, GPA: 79%

2013 – 2015 Applied Science Certificate

Columbia College

University Transfer Program, GPA: 3.5/4.0

## LANGUAGES

### **INTERESTS**

### English - proficient Russian - proficient Kazakh - native

- Automated and adaptable network security bots

- SSL Proxy in session-based approach

- DevOps

- Serverless and scalable web applications

- Participating in Hackathon events (Recent:

VanHacks 2020)

# KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded for creating the most useful Android app (2017)
- The Malcom C. J. Wickson Memorial Award (2020)

## **ELECTIVE COURSES**

- Cryptography
- Leadership
- Project Management
- Management Strategy